ORIGINAL STORY SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
LAST WORLD FAN FESTIVAL
VIP TESTER EVENT
APPLY
YOU HAVE APPLIED AS A VIP TESTER
Hyun-su, how long are you
going to behave like that?
-What?
-Honey.
Dad, why are you ruining the mood?
Then when else would I be
able to talk to him?
He never leaves his room.
Why are you ruining your own life?
Stop it. This is a family trip.
Hyun-su came out to join us.
So what?
Should I be impressed?
Fuck.
What?
You make me sick.
I'm so grateful you earn money for us
just to neglect your own son.
-You little brat.
-Hey, what's wrong with you?
Shut up, Su-a.
You're ashamed of me, aren't you?
Are you scared you'll end up like me?
I heard you talking shit with your friend.
-That's…
-Hyun-su, calm down.
You're no different, Mom.
You suggested it.
Did you think I wouldn't know?
Hyun-su…
I thought you were strong enough
to overcome it.
I'm not! How could I?
Cha Hyun-su! You brat!
You should all just die.
Dad!
He's awake! Hyun-su's awake!
I didn't think you'd wake up.
How long was I unconscious?
A pretty long time.
I had a dream…
A dream? What dream?
I can't remember it now.
I heard somebody was moving
into Room 1410. I guess that's you.
-Living alone?
-A loner?
You'll just cause trouble…
Find somewhere else to die.
A slow speaker.
-I'll protect you.
-Protect them?
Is that what you want?
That's what dreams are like.
Uncle…
I want to be alone for a while.
All right. Call me if you need any help.
You should live a decent life now.
At least for your dead family.
I'm sure there's a reason
you're the only one who survived.
Did I have an uncle?
Isn't it cool?
It's what you wanted. You wanted
everyone in the world to disappear.
-You should all just die.
-"You should all just die."
I can make everyone you hate disappear.
And I can do even more than that.
I am you.
All you have to do is accept that.
Sir, what's wrong?
Yeong-su, pull!
Wake up!
Come on!
Did you hear that?
Yes.
It's pretty loud.
Maybe it's the guy we saw.
What's God's will?
I'm sure it isn't to be selfish
and ignore others.
Run!
Hurry!
Are you okay?
Who are…
The kids.
What about the kids?
You're infected, aren't you?
Your nose was bleeding and you fainted!
-You're the one who wanted to save him.
-Are you sure he won't turn?
I'm sure crushing his head in right now
is not the will of God.
Help me.
Please help me.
I made a promise.
Help me.
Please.
Su-yeong, is he not coming back?
Is he dead?
We have to go on our own.
But…
It's okay. I won't tell anyone.
Let's go.
I…
can't see.
Where are you?
I think I should tell you in advance.
They're not infected.
There aren't any monsters around here.
Let's go.
I can't see!
You might meet a monster that can't see.
His hearing is really good.
Don't make any noise.
And don't move.
I can't see…
I found you.
No!
Su-yeong, he told us
that it was Room 1408.
This is the 15th floor, though.
We can't go there now.
The monsters are fighting there.
Su-yeong…
There might be some grown-ups
who can help us.
Hello? Is there anyone in there?
Please help us!
Help us!
Close your eyes.
Su-yeong…
I said to close your eyes, Kim Yeong-su!
I'LL SEE YOU AGAIN, ASSHOLE
PRESIDENT'S EMERGENCY STATEMENT
My fellow citizens,
we are declaring a state of emergency.
Do not leave your homes.
The monsters are extremely dangerous.
Don't touch the children.
You can do that, right?
The government will prioritize
the citizens' safety…
and…
What?
As if! Shit!
Everyone is going to die.
You're all fucked!
You're going to die.
Die!
What?
Is the president dead?
Gosh. I voted for him.
But still, they'll come and save us.
Are you deaf?
He just said we're all fucked!
-What's wrong with him?
-Seung-wan, what's wrong?
My poor daughter…
No…
Da-eun…
No!
Da-eun?
To be honest,
I already knew.
I knew…
that my baby was gone.
Kids, run.
Hurry!
Come on.
How do we kill that thing?
Take the kids and run!
Come to Room 1408!
Ji-su,
I'll take care of this.
Even those great muscles…
can't compete with this, I guess.
You're lousier than I thought.
He'll kill you.
Right? You piece of meat.
All right, that's it.
Ma'am, are you okay?
What about the kids?
There's no greater love than laying down
one's life for their friends.
If you do as God commands, you're…
His friend.
Amen.
They're safe.
I can go by myself from here.
Make sure to come, okay?
Okay.
I'll see you in Room 1408.
Who are you?
Ji-su.
I'm glad you're okay.
Do you want to die that badly?
I get that you like God,
but you can go meet him later.
God is omnipresent.
-Come on!
-Okay.
Ji-su, wait.
Someone must have been here.
You're pretty rude sometimes.
You're the first one to visit my room.
Oh, is your room usually…
It's not usually this bad.
Okay.
Ji-su.
Aren't you going to take that?
NOW IT'S YOURS
This is yours, right?
Hey, you got the job!
Congrats…
This is all useless, Mom.
I've studied so hard for five years,
but the world is over now.
The president's death
doesn't mean it's over.
We don't know that.
You're jumping to conclusions.
As if! Shit!
Everyone is going to die.
You're all fucked!
-Ma'am, turn that off, will you?
-You're going to die. Die!
It's getting on my nerves.
Stop calling me "ma'am."
You're such an asshole.
"Asshole"? Right…
Have you seen my sister?
Eun-yu?
I haven't seen her for a while now.
Weren't you with her?
No.
I guess he was pretty flustered, too.
He doesn't even know where his sister is.
Bom, I promise I'll never leave your side.
Come and sit.
Okay.
Enjoy.
Let's eat.
Kids,
what are your names?
I'm Kim Yeong-su.
I'm Kim Su-yeong.
Kim Yeong-su and Kim Su-yeong.
Yeong-su and Su-yeong…
They're peculiar names…
I guess your parents
gave you similar names,
so you two would always stick together.
Yeong-su and Su-yeong. Right?
Dad named us…
Dad…
Thank you.
It's all right. I don't really drink.
You sure know how to drink.
-Here, you can have one, too.
-Oh, I'm…
Oh, right. You're a minor.
Right. There are kids here,
so let's not break the law. I'll buy you
a drink when you become an adult.
You should learn how to drink from adults.
Do you think…
that day will come?
ELECTRICAL ROOM
The electricity's back on,
but why hasn't she returned yet?
Isn't there a security camera
in the basement?
The camera's been turned like that.
I told her it was too dangerous.
Didn't I tell her, Bom?
Let's wait a bit longer.
Hey, it's your turn.
-What?
-It's your turn to stand watch.
I'm infected.
I know.
If I turn,
kill me.
Sorry.
What?
If I turn…
kill me and I'll do the same for you.
Okay?
Okay.
This is so selfish!
GREEN SUPERMARKET
Hang on.
Seok-hyeon, it's me, Byeong-il.
You shouldn't do this to me!
I'm not running a charity here.
Bring money if you want something!
This is insane.
What…
GREEN SUPERMARKET
Who is he?
You're Room 802, right?
What happened to your face?
I couldn't recognize you.
Were you here the whole time?
No, I came down earlier tonight.
Tonight?
Your face looks awful.
Did something happen on the way down?
Oh, this?
I got hurt a while ago.
A burglar broke into my house.
-A burglar?
A burglar in this building?
What's he doing?
-My goodness.
-There's food!
We can share.
Thank you so much.
Take this.
-I'm sure you'll be blessed.
-We should all help each other, right?
-Thank you.
-I got this, too.
Thank you. We're saved now.
Here.
Take this.
It's all right.
Take as much as you want.
Thank you.
Help yourself.
What are you doing?
I've been watching since dawn.
I think it's safe outside.
All the monsters are gone.
You're thinking of going out?
Do you want to die in here, then?
-If I can get to the car…
-Then take me, too!
My mom lives in Wangsimni.
Please just take me there.
I'll have to take a detour if--
Please.
-It's too far.
-Please. Come on.
Is it nice to eat free food like a beggar?
You could've given me some food, too.
Buy some with your money!
How can you treat me like this?
What's this sound?
Tell them to turn it off!
They turn it on every morning.
You used to dance to it.
Hey, don't you remember that monster
with the tongue?
It's going to hear that
and come back here!
Gosh, you startled me.
How can it hear that and come here?
That's ridiculous.
Do you think it only has a tongue?
It has ears, too!
It must have ears! It's going to hear it!
Tell them to stop that!
Survivors in the building,
take any food, medicine, and weapons
you have and come to the first floor.
The first floor is quite safe for now,
and it'll be safer to stay together.
We survivors…
must stick together.
Please come down.
Please.
I repeat--
-What's wrong with you?
-What are you doing?
-My daughter!
-Hold her!
-Let me go!
-Why are you doing this?
-What's going on?
-Let me out!
What's going on here?
Look. My daughter's here.
-My daughter's here!
-Lower the shutters.
Don't!
Let me go!
Let me go! Wait!
My daughter's here!
Min-ju! Run!
-Min-ju!
-Mom!
Min-ju!
-Min-ju!
-Mom!
Shouldn't we do something?
We need to decide now!
Mom!
What do we do?
My daughter…
BASED ON WEBTOON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
Subtitle translation by Ju-young Park
Modify by Blue-Bird™